

## **GRANT LEASURE**

grleasure@gmail.com | 310-948-6661 | 1431 W 172nd St , Gardena , CA 90247

Summary

My career in the restaurant industry started at McCormick and Schmicks. I began as a Back Server and within three months I was promoted to Server. Due to hard work and determination, I was the first Back Server to be promoted at that location in seven years. After a year and a half at McCormick and Schmicks I was recruited to work at Chart House, another fine dining establishment, where I furthered my knowledge of hospitality and sales. During my time at Chart House, I came upon the opportunity to work at True Food Kitchen. A new concept restaurant that focuses on health and nutrition as well as gastronomy and hospitality. The True Food culture aims to accommodate every guest's needs and go above and beyond to make every experience exceptional. In this environment is where I have continued to further my knowledge in allergies, dietary restrictions, nutritional values and ingredients.

As I continue to progress, management has become more and more appealing as the next step of growth in this industry. As I am eager to continue to expand my knowledge and take on more responsibility, I am confident I will thrive in anything I set my mind to.

Skills

- Special dietary requirements
- Food safety understanding
- Wine pairings
- High-volume dining
- Effective customer up-selling
- Menu knowledge
- Liquor, wine and food service
- Relationship management
- In-depth food and wine knowledge

- Service prioritization
- Effective sales techniques
- Safe food handling
- Seating assignment preparation
- Point of Sale (POS) system operations
- Menu memorization
- Prompt table clearance
- Check payment processing
- Dining customer service

Experience

## **Server**True Food Kitchen | El Segundo, CA

Highest preforming server in alcohol and food sales.

- Maintained table settings by removing courses, replacing utensils and refilling beverages promptly.
- Arranged each place setting attractively and verified all items were clean and free from water spots and chips.
- Operated POS terminals to input orders, split bills and calculate totals.
- Discussed alternative selections with chef for guests with food allergies or gluten-free requests.
- Satisfied customers by keeping drinks topped off and anticipating needs such as condiments and extra napkins.
- Communicated effectively with kitchen staff regarding customer allergies, dietary needs and other special requests.
- Promoted desserts, appetizers and specialty drinks.
- Recommended daily specials, wine selections and desserts to guide patrons toward more profitable items.
- Maximized team performance by training new employees on proper food handling, guest expectations and restaurant protocols.
- Checked patrons' identification to ensure minimum age requirements for consumption of alcoholic beverages.

**Server** 01/2018 - 06/2019

Chart House | Redondo Beach, CA

- Maximized team performance by training new employees on proper food handling, guest expectations and restaurant protocols.
- Assisted individuals in selecting meal options, including entrees and desserts and recommended alternative items for those with food allergies and gluten intolerances.
- Operated POS terminals to input orders, split bills and calculate totals.
- Arranged each place setting attractively and verified all items were clean and free from water spots and chips
- Placed reservations through phone and email into OpenTable.
- Communicated effectively with kitchen staff regarding customer allergies, dietary needs and other special requests.
- Maintained table settings by removing courses, replacing utensils and refilling beverages promptly.
- Recommended daily specials, wine selections and desserts to guide patrons toward more profitable items.

## Server, Banquet Server

02/2017 - 02/2018

01/2018 - Current

McCormick & Schmicks | El Segundo, CA

- Communicated effectively with kitchen staff regarding customer allergies, dietary needs and other special requests.
- Checked patrons' identification to ensure minimum age requirements for consumption of alcoholic beverages.
- Maintained table settings by removing courses, replacing utensils and refilling beverages promptly.
- Operated POS terminals to input orders, split bills and calculate totals.
- Maximized team performance by training new employees on proper food handling, guest expectations and restaurant protocols.
- Arranged each place setting attractively and verified all items were clean and free from water spots and chips.
- Recommended daily specials, wine selections and desserts to guide patrons toward more profitable items.

Education and Training

**BBA**: Business Management